<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="S24_DH289schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<xml>
    <header>
        <citationInfo>
            <journalTitle>The Western Spy, and Hamilton Gazette</journalTitle>
            <publicationDate when="1802-12-01"></publicationDate>
            <publicationPlace settlement="Cincinnati" state="Ohio">Cincinnati, Ohio</publicationPlace>
            <page>5</page>
            <adUrl>https://proctorf.github.io/HIST289SharedS24/images/Billy.png</adUrl>
        </citationInfo>
        <respDesc>
            <created resp="" when="2024-03-27">Created by Izzi Howard</created>
        </respDesc>
    </header>
    <transcript>
        <p>Twenty Dollars Reward</p>
        <p>Ran away from the subscriber living in Pendleton county, state of Kentucky, near the folks of licking, on the 11th of October last, a negro man named Billy, about 37 or 38 years old, of a rather low stature, well set and strong built, had his head generally neatly combed and his carlocks plated or twisted, which he sometimes tied together at the back of his head, and sometimes let them hang down, which was remarkable in a black negro as he is, though his complexion is none of the blackest. As to his clothing he had on when he went away a coarse linsey coat, two shirt and two overalls, and a fur hat about half worn- he had other clothing which he took away, viz. a new coat jacket and breeches of flax and cotton of a pale blue color. But as he is a cunning, artful villain, it is probable that he has changed his clothing and cut his hair. It is also probable that he may have a forged pass; as there are white men mean enough to forge the like; and sometimes I think he eloped with and under the protection of some white villains as his owner. If stripped; his back will show visible marks of the whip. It is likely too he may attempt to pass as a free man, as he is a tolerable good rough carpenter and house joiner- Whoever secures him for me so that I get him, either by bringing him to me, or putting him in some public jail, shall recieve the above reward.</p>
        <p>Francis Flournoy.</p>
    </transcript>
    <footer>
        <adType type="enslaver"></adType>
        <rewardInfo>
            <amount minAmount="20">Twenty Dollars</amount>
        </rewardInfo>
        <listPerson>
            <persName xml:id="" role="enslaved" sex="m" foreName="Billy"><characteristics>
                <physical>
                    <build>rather low stature, well set and strong built, carlocks plated or twisted</build>
                    <phenotype>black complexion</phenotype>  
                    <scars>back will show visible marks of the whip</scars>
                    <minAge years="37"></minAge>
                    <maxAge years="38"></maxAge>
                    <clothing>a coarse linsey coat, two shirt and two overalls, and a fur hat, a new coat jacket and breeches of flax and cotton of a pale blue color</clothing>
                </physical>
                <countenance><passAsFree pass="y">he eloped with and under the protection of some white villains</passAsFree></countenance>
                <otherFeatures><papersDesc papers="y">may have a forged pass</papersDesc><hadHelp>he eloped with and under the protection of some white villains</hadHelp></otherFeatures>
            </characteristics></persName>
            <persName xml:id="" role="enslaver" sex="m" foreName="Francis" surName="Flournoy">
               <characteristics>
                   <physical></physical>
                   <countenance></countenance>
                   <otherFeatures></otherFeatures>
               </characteristics>
            </persName>
        </listPerson>
        <listPlace>
            <placeName placeType="origin" county="Pendleton" state="KY"></placeName>
        </listPlace>
    </footer>
</xml>
