<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="S24_DH289schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<xml>
 <header>
     <citationInfo>
         <journalTitle>The Western Star</journalTitle>
         <publicationDate when="1812-04-18"></publicationDate>
         <publicationPlace settlement="Lebanon" state="Ohio"></publicationPlace>
         <page>4</page>
     </citationInfo>
     <respDesc>
         <created resp="TT" when="2024-04-09"></created>
     </respDesc>
 </header>   
    <transcript>Forty Dollars Reward,
        
        RAN-AWAY from the subscriber on Saturday the 28th ult. Living in boon county, Kentucky, 
        eighteen miles below the mouth of Licking, near the Ohio - a NEGRO man named,
        
        BOB
        
        Hi is about twenty years of age, very black, down look, five feet five or six inches high, 
        well made, he took away with him a large yellow dog named ROVER, blind of one eye, 
        the eye is not sunk, a dark colored cloth coat 2 pair of pantalons one of blue cloth, 
        the other tow lined, a pair of old fair lo boots, one pair of old shoes, 
        one or two waist coats(not recollected what kind,) no other clothing recollected. 
        Whoever will apprehend said Runaway and secure him in either Warren or Hamilton county jail 
        and give information so that i get him againshall recieve the above reward 
        - and if deliverd to the subscriber living in Kentucky they shall have the reward aforesaid, 
        together with all reasonable charges - paid by me,
        
        Edmund Garnett.
        
        Boon country, (KY.
        April 4, 1812 [241]]}
        
        N.B. The subscriber has been informed that has altered his name to Reusem since he ranaway, he has also heared that he has exchanged his clothes
        He has been seen a few miles from Lebanon enquiring for that place.
        E.G.
    
    </transcript>
    <footer>
        <adType type="enslaver"></adType>
        <rewardInfo>
            <amount minAmount="40"></amount>
        </rewardInfo>
        <listPerson>
            <persName xml:id="" role="enslaved" sex="m" foreName="Bob" alias="Reusem"> <characteristics>
                <physical>
                    <clothing>a dark colored cloth coat 2 pair of pantalons one of blue cloth, 
                        the other tow lined, a pair of old fair lo boots, one pair of old shoes, 
                        one or two waist coats</clothing>
                    <build>down look</build>
                    <phenotype>negro</phenotype>
                    <minHeight inches="65"></minHeight>
                    <maxHeight inches="66"></maxHeight>
                    <maxAge years="20"></maxAge>
                    <possessions>Yellow Dog Named Rover</possessions>
                </physical>
                <countenance>
                </countenance>
                <otherFeatures>
                </otherFeatures>
            </characteristics></persName>
        </listPerson>
        <listPlace>
            <placeName placeType="potential destination" country="USA" county="Warren, Hamilton" settlement="Boon" state="Kentucky"></placeName>
        </listPlace>
    </footer>
    
</xml>
