<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../Shared%20drives/HIST289%20Course%20Materials/3%20-%20XML%20TEI/XML%20Assignment/S24_DH289schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<xml>
    <header>
        <citationInfo>
            <journalTitle>Charleston Courier</journalTitle>
            <publicationDate when="1840-01-07">January 7, 1840</publicationDate>
            <publicationPlace settlement="Cincinnati" state="Ohio">Cincinnati, OH</publicationPlace>
            <page>6</page>
            <url>https://github.com/proctorf/HIST289SharedS24/blob/main/images/XMLad_My.png</url>
            
        </citationInfo>
        
        <respDesc>
            <created resp="ftp" when="2025-03-27">Created by My Bui</created>
        </respDesc>
    </header>
    
    <transcript>
        RANAWAY FROM the subscriber, on Monday the twenty-first: inst. my negro man MILLER, about twenty-eight or thirty years of age; about six feet high; straight made, tolerably black colour; wide mouth; thick lips; fat nose, and has lost 3 or 4 of his upper fore teeth, weighing about 175 lbs. rawboned and a very stout man. One of his heels is considerably larger than the other, and appears to be swollen, occasioned from his having had the white swelling, and has a noted scar or sore on the back part of his neck, about the size of the palm of a man's hand, and generally wears a black patch over it. He had on when he went away, an old blue jeans coat, and a new pair of white linsy pantaloons; and took with him a variety of other clothing not recollected. He is a very intelligent fellow, and it is probable he will aim to get into a free State, and will procure a free pass. Any person that will apprehend the said fellow, and bring him home to me, at my house in Anderson county, 5 miles from Lawrenceburg, near the road leading to Harrodsburg, shall receive a reward of $15 if taken in either of the adjoining counties, or twenty dollars, if taken out of said counties and in the State, or a likely young Negro to be worth one hundred and fifty dollars, if taken out of the State and brought home. NATH'L. B. MEAUX.
        P. S. The above described fellow, ranaway without any provocation whatever. All reasonable expences will be paid in addition to the $15 and $20. I am not positive as to the number of teeth he has out. Dec. 29. 1829
    </transcript>
    <footer>
        <adType type="Runaway "></adType>
        <rewardInfo>
            <amount minAmount="15" maxAmount="150"></amount>
        </rewardInfo>
        <listPerson>
            <persName xml:id="" role="enslaved person" sex="m" foreName="Miller">
                <characteristics>
                    <physical>
                        <phenotype>Straight made, tolerably black colour; wide mouth; thick lips; fat nose, rawboned and a very stout man.</phenotype>
                        <minAge years="28"></minAge>
                        <maxAge years="30"></maxAge>
                        <maxHeight inches="72"></maxHeight>
                        <build>Straight made, rawboned, and very stout</build>
                        <clothing>He had on when he went away, an old blue jeans coat, and a new pair of white linsy pantaloons; and took with him a variety of other clothing not recollected.</clothing>
                        <scars>A noted scar or sore on the back part of his neck, about the size of the palm of a man's hand, and generally wears a black patch over it.</scars>
                        <teeth>Lost 3 or 4 of his upper fore teeth.</teeth>
                    </physical>
                    <countenance>
                        <behavior>ranaway without any provocation whatever.</behavior>
                        <other></other>
                    </countenance>
                    <otherFeatures>
                        <literate>a very intelligent fellow.></literate>
                    </otherFeatures>
                </characteristics>
            </persName>
        </listPerson>
        <listPerson>
            <persName xml:id="" role="enslaver" sex="m" foreName="NATH'L. B. MEAUX.">
                <enslaverInfo>
                </enslaverInfo>
            </persName>
        </listPerson>
        <listPlace>
            <placeName placeType="enslaver's house">Anderson county, 5 miles from Lawrenceburg, near the road leading to Harrodsburg.</placeName>
        </listPlace>
    </footer>
    
</xml>