<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<?xml-model href="S24_DH289schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<xml>
    <header>
        <citationInfo>
            <journalTitle>Scocioto Gazette</journalTitle>
            <publicationDate when="1810-01-13">January 13, 1810</publicationDate>
            <publicationPlace settlement="Chillicothe" state="Ohio">Chillicothe, OH</publicationPlace>
            <page>6</page>
            <adUrl>https://github.com/proctorf/HIST289SharedS24/blob/main/images/nancy-tran/1810_Aaron_ScociotoGazette.png</adUrl>
            
        </citationInfo>
        
        <respDesc>
            <created resp="ftp" when="2024-04-08">Created by Nancy Tran</created>
        </respDesc>
    </header>
    
    
    <transcript>
        <p>A Runaway Negro</p>
        <p>Ran-Away from the subscriber, living in <place ref = "Clark county, KY" placeType="origin">Clarke county, Kentucky</place>, on the
            <date dateType="departure" when="1809-12-20"> 20th of December, 1809 </date> a Negro Man named</p>
        <p>
            <name xml:id="">
                <hi rend="allCaps">Aaron</hi>
            </name>
        </p>
        <p>, around thirty-siz years of age, judged to he about five feet six inches high, very artful, 
            has a scar on his forehead, and I believe a split in one of his finger nails; he carried with
            him a black pair of linsey overalls, also one black pair of condutoy overalls, a blue broad-cloth
            surtout coat, a brown great-coat, a black sattin wast-coast, an old fur hat dressed over, a pair 
            of shoes laced up before, and a pair of boots; but it is probable he may have changed both his 
            clothes and his names. It is expected some person has given him a pass. He took away with him a 
            dark bay Horse, about 14 and 1-2 bands high, with a blushy tail, and I believe he has a small
            star on in his foreheed, but cannot recollect whether he is branded or not. I expect he will 
            cross<place
                placeType="destination">Ohio</place>. 
            Besides what the law allows, I will liberally reward any person who will deliver said Negro man
            and horse, or either of them, to me, or secure said Negro man in any jail in the United States 
            so that I can get him again. Whoever takes him up must be extremely cautious or he will make his
            escape.
        </p>
        <p>
            <name xml:id="">Reichard Hickman</name>
        </p>
        <p>
            <date dateType="dateWritten" when="1810-01-04">January 04,1810</date>
        </p>
    </transcript>
    
    <footer>
        <adType type="enslaver"/>
        <rewardInfo>
            <amount minAmount="0"></amount>
            <criteria>deliver said Negro man and horse, or either of them, to me, or secure said Negro man
                in any jail in the United States so that I can get him again</criteria>
        </rewardInfo>
        <listPerson>
            <persName xml:id="" role="enslaved" sex="m" foreName="Aaron"
                >Aaron
                <characteristics>
                    <physical>
                        
                        <build> has a scar on his forehead, and I believe a 
                            split in one of his finger nails </build>
                        <minHeight inches="66">five feet siz inches</minHeight>
                        <minAge years="36"> about thirty-six years of age</minAge>
                        <clothing>a black pair of linsey overalls, also one black pair of condutoy overalls,
                            a blue broad-cloth surtout coat, a brown great-coat, a black sattin wast-coast,
                            an old fur hat dressed over, a pair of shoes laced up before, and a pair of boots</clothing>
                    </physical>
                    
                    <countenance>
                        <behavior>very artful</behavior>
                        <passAsFree pass="y">some person has given him a pass</passAsFree>
                    </countenance>
                    
                    <otherFeatures>
                        <horse hadHorse="y">dark bay Horse, about 14 and 1-2 bands high, with a bushy tail, and I believe he has 
                            a small star in his forehead, but cannot recollect whether he is branded or not </horse>
                       
                    </otherFeatures>
                </characteristics>
            </persName>
            
            <persName xml:id="" role="enslaver" sex="m" foreName="Reichard" surName="Hickman">Reichard Hickman <characteristics>
                <physical></physical>
                <countenance></countenance>
                <otherFeatures></otherFeatures>
            </characteristics></persName>
        </listPerson>
        
        <listPlace>
            <placeName county="Clark" placeType="origin" state="Kentucky"
                country="USA" geo="37.9700, -84.1500"> Clark county, Kentucky </placeName>
            
            <placeName placeType="destination" state="Ohio" country="USA"
                geo="40.367474, -82.996216">Ohio</placeName>
            
            <placeName placeType="destination" geo ="">Ohio</placeName>
        </listPlace>
        
        
    </footer>
</xml>